<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<contents number="7" title="Networks and Internet">

<!-- word 1 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Asymmetric digital subscriber line</word>
    <acronym>ADSL</acronym>
    <description>Asymmetric Digital Subscriber Line (ADSL) is a type of digital subscriber line technology, a data communications technology that enables faster data transmission over copper telephone lines than a conventional voiceband modem can provide. It does this by utilizing frequencies that are not used by a voice telephone call. A splitter, or DSL filter, allows a single telephone connection to be used for both ADSL service and voice calls at the same time. ADSL can generally only be distributed over short distances from the telephone exchange (the last mile), typically less than 4 kilometres (2 mi), but has been known to exceed 8 kilometres if the originally laid wire gauge allows for further distribution.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ADSL</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fe/ADSL_router_with_Wi-Fi_%28802.11_b-g%29.jpg/220px-ADSL_router_with_Wi-Fi_%28802.11_b-g%29.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 2 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Bandwidth</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Bandwidth is the difference between the upper and lower frequencies in a continuous set of frequencies. It is typically measured in hertz, and may sometimes refer to passband bandwidth, sometimes to baseband bandwidth, depending on context. Passband bandwidth is the difference between the upper and lower cutoff frequencies of, for example, an electronic filter, a communication channel, or a signal spectrum. In case of a low-pass filter or baseband signal, the bandwidth is equal to its upper cutoff frequency. The term baseband bandwidth always refers to the upper cutoff frequency, regardless of whether the filter is bandpass or low-pass.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bandwidth_%28signal_processing%29</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/thumb/4/48/Baseband.svg/300px-Baseband.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 3 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Kilobit per second</word>
    <acronym>KBit/s</acronym>
    <description>A kibibit per second (Kibit/s or Kib/s) is a unit of data transfer rate equal to 1,024 bits per second. The word "kibibit" is not capitalized, but the abbreviation "Kits" is.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_rate_units#Kibibit_per_second</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 4 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Megabit per second</word>
    <acronym>MBit/s</acronym>
    <description>A megabit per second (Mbit/s, Mb/s, or Mbps; not to be confused with mbit/s which means, literally, millibit per second) is a unit of data transfer rate equal to:
    1,000,000 bits per second or
    1,000 kilobits per second or
    125,000 bytes per second.
    125 kilobytes per second.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Data_rate_units#Megabit_per_second</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 5 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Direct Connect</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Direct connect is a peer-to-peer file sharing protocol. Direct connect clients connect to a central hub and can download files directly from one another. Advanced Direct Connect can be considered a successor protocol.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Direct_Connect_%28file_sharing%29</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 6 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Download</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computer networks, to download means to receive data to a local system from a remote system, or to initiate such a data transfer. Examples of a remote system from which a download might be performed include a web server, FTP server, email server, or other similar systems.
A download can mean either any file that is offered for downloading or that has been downloaded, or the process of receiving such a file.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Download</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/40/Download.svg/90px-Download.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 7 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Ethernet</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Ethernet is a family of computer networking technologies for local area networks (LANs). Ethernet was commercially introduced in 1980 and standardized in 1985 as IEEE 802.3. Ethernet has largely replaced competing wired LAN technologies.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d7/Ethernet_RJ45_connector_p1160054.jpg/220px-Ethernet_RJ45_connector_p1160054.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 8 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Internet</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The Internet is a global system of interconnected computer networks that use the standard Internet protocol suite (often called TCP/IP, although not all applications use TCP) to serve billions of users worldwide. It is a network of networks that consists of millions of private, public, academic, business, and government networks, of local to global scope, that are linked by a broad array of electronic, wireless and optical networking technologies. The Internet carries an extensive range of information resources and services, such as the inter-linked hypertext documents of the World Wide Web (WWW) and the infrastructure to support email.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Internet</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d2/Internet_map_1024.jpg/150px-Internet_map_1024.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 9 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Client server model</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The client server model is a computing model that acts as a distributed application which partitions tasks or workloads between the providers of a resource or service, called servers, and service requesters, called clients. Often clients and servers communicate over a computer network on separate hardware, but both client and server may reside in the same system. A server machine is a host that is running one or more server programs which share their resources with clients. A client does not share any of its resources, but requests a server's content or service function. Clients therefore initiate communication sessions with servers which await incoming requests.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Client%E2%80%93server_model</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c9/Client-server-model.svg/220px-Client-server-model.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 10 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Peer to peer model</word>
    <acronym>P2P</acronym>
    <description>A peer to peer (abbreviated to P2P) computer network is one in which each computer in the network can act as a client or server for the other computers in the network, allowing shared access to various resources such as files, peripherals, and sensors without the need for a central server. P2P networks can be set up within the home, a business, or over the Internet. Each network type requires all computers in the network to use the same or a compatible program to connect to each other and access files and other resources found on the other computer. P2P networks can be used for sharing content such as audio, video, data, or anything in digital format.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Peer-to-peer</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3f/P2P-network.svg/200px-P2P-network.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 11 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Modulator Demodulator</word>
    <acronym>Modem</acronym>
    <description>A modem (modulator demodulator) is a device that modulates an analog carrier signal to encode digital information, and also demodulates such a carrier signal to decode the transmitted information. The goal is to produce a signal that can be transmitted easily and decoded to reproduce the original digital data. Modems can be used over any means of transmitting analog signals, from light emitting diodes to radio. The most familiar example is a voice band modem that turns the digital data of a personal computer into modulated electrical signals in the voice frequency range of a telephone channel. These signals can be transmitted over telephone lines and demodulated by another modem at the receiver side to recover the digital data.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modem</link>
	<image>http://www.microsoft.com/library/media/1033/windowsxp/images/using/networking/setup/68573-router-diagram.gif</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 12 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Port</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computer networking a port is an application-specific or process-specific software construct serving as a communications endpoint in a computer's host operating system. A port is associated with an IP address of the host, as well as the type of protocol used for communication. The protocols that primarily use the ports are the Transport Layer protocols, such as the Transmission Control Protocol (TCP) and the User Datagram Protocol (UDP) of the Internet Protocol Suite. A port is identified for each address and protocol by a 16-bit number, commonly known as the port number. The port number completes the destination address for a communications session. Thus, different IP addresses or protocols may use the same port number for communication, e.g. on a given host or interface UDP and TCP may use the same port number, or on a host with two interfaces, both addresses are associated with a port having the same number.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Port_(computer_networking)</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 13 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Protocol</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A communications protocol is a system of digital message formats and rules for exchanging messages in or between computing systems and in .A protocol may have a formal description.
Protocols may include signaling, authentication and error detection and correction capabilities.
A protocol is a set of rule and regulation required for synchronization of communication; the specified behavior is typically independent of how it is to be implemented. A protocol can therefore be implemented as hardware or software or both in the communication system.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Communications_protocol</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 14 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Router</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A router is a device that forwards data packets between computer networks, creating an overlay internetwork. A router is connected to two or more data lines from different networks. When a data packet comes in on one of the lines, the router reads the address information in the packet to determine its ultimate destination. Then, using information in its routing table or routing policy, it directs the packet to the next network on its journey. Routers perform the "traffic directing" functions on the Internet. A data packet is typically forwarded from one router to another through the networks that constitute the internetwork until it gets to its destination node.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Router_%28computing%29</link>
	<image>http://www.microsoft.com/library/media/1033/windowsxp/images/using/networking/setup/68573-router-diagram.gif</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 15 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Local Area Network</word>
    <acronym>LAN</acronym>
    <description>A local area network (LAN) is a computer network that interconnects computers in a limited area such as a home, school, computer laboratory, or office building using network media.[1] The defining characteristics of LANs, in contrast to wide area networks (WANs), include their usually higher data-transfer rates, smaller geographic area, and lack of a need for leased telecommunication lines.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Local_Area_Network</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 16 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Wireless Area Network</word>
    <acronym>WAN</acronym>
    <description>A wireless local area network (WLAN) links two or more devices using some wireless distribution method (typically spread-spectrum or OFDM radio), and usually providing a connection through an access point to the wider internet. This gives users the mobility to move around within a local coverage area and still be connected to the network. Most modern WLANs are based on IEEE 802.11 standards, marketed under the Wi-Fi brand name.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wireless_area_network</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/8b/Wireless_network.jpg/220px-Wireless_network.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 17 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Digital sign</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A digital signal is a physical signal that is a representation of a sequence of discrete values (a quantified discrete-time signal), for example of an arbitrary bit stream, or of a digitized (sampled and analog-to-digital converted) analog signal. The term digital signal can refer to
    1. a continuous-time waveform signal used in any form of digital communication.
    2. a pulse train signal that switches between a discrete number of voltage levels or levels of light intensity, also known as a line coded signal, for example a signal found in digital electronics or in serial communications using digital baseband transmission, or a pulse code modulation (PCM) representation of a digitized analog signal.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_signal</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 18 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Analog sign</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>An analog or analogue signal is any continuous signal for which the time varying feature (variable) of the signal is a representation of some other time varying quantity, i.e., analogous to another time varying signal.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Analog_signal</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 19 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Server</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In most common use, a server is a physical computer (a computer hardware system) dedicated to running one or more services (as a host), to serve the needs of the users of other computers on the network. Depending on the computing service that it offers it could be a database server, file server, mail server, print server, web server, gaming server, or some other kind of server.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Server_%28computing%29</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f5/Rack001.jpg/220px-Rack001.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 20 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Spam</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Spam is the use of electronic messaging systems to send unsolicited bulk messages, especially advertising, indiscriminately. While the most widely recognized form of spam is e-mail spam, the term is applied to similar abuses in other media: instant messaging spam, Usenet newsgroup spam, Web search engine spam, spam in blogs, wiki spam, online classified ads spam, mobile phone messaging spam, Internet forum spam, junk fax transmissions, social networking spam, social spam, television advertising and file sharing network spam.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Spam_%28electronic%29</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/97/Viagra_Spam_Mail_2011.png/300px-Viagra_Spam_Mail_2011.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 21 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Upload</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Upload files. Transmit files or information from the sender to the receiver computer. Operation counter to download. The upload connection to a network (Internet) refers to the total rate (usually measured in megabytes or mbps) with information that can be transferred from the computer out.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uploading_and_downloading</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 22 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Transmission Control Protocol and Internet Protocol</word>
    <acronym>TCP/IP</acronym>
    <description>TCP/IP provides end-to-end connectivity specifying how data should be formatted, addressed, transmitted, routed and received at the destination. It has four abstraction layers, each with its own protocols.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TCP/IP_model</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 23 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Wireless</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Wireless telecommunications is the transfer of information between two or more points that are not physically connected. Distances can be short, such as a few metres for television remote control, or as far as thousands or even millions of kilometres for deep-space radio communications. It encompasses various types of fixed, mobile, and portable two-way radios, cellular telephones, personal digital assistants (PDAs), and wireless networking.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Wireless</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 24 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>WiFi</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Wi-Fi is a popular technology that allows an electronic device to exchange data wirelessly (using radio waves) over a computer network, including high-speed Internet connections.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WiFi</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/32/Wi-Fi_Logo.svg/220px-Wi-Fi_Logo.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 25 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Bluetooth</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Bluetooth is a proprietary open wireless technology standard for exchanging data over short distances (using short wavelength radio transmissions in the ISM band from 2400 a 2480 MHz) from fixed and mobile devices, creating personal area networks (PANs) with high levels of security. Created by telecoms vendor Ericsson in 1994, it was originally conceived as a wireless alternative to RS 232 data cables. It can connect several devices, overcoming problems of synchronization.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bluetooth</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fc/BluetoothLogo.svg/200px-BluetoothLogo.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 26 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Ethernet hub</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>An Ethernet hub, active hub, network hub, repeater hub, multiport repeater or hub is a device for connecting multiple Ethernet devices together and making them act as a single network segment. It has multiple input/output (I/O) ports, in which a signal introduced at the input of any port appears at the output of every port except the original incoming. A hub works at the physical layer (layer 1) of the OSI model. The device is a form of multiport repeater. Repeater hubs also participate in collision detection, forwarding a jam signal to all ports if it detects a collision.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ethernet_hub</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d9/4_port_netgear_ethernet_hub.jpg/300px-4_port_netgear_ethernet_hub.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 27 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Internet Protocol address</word>
    <acronym>IP address</acronym>
    <description>An Internet Protocol address (IP address) is a numerical label assigned to each device (e.g., computer, printer) participating in a computer network that uses the Internet Protocol for communication. An IP address serves two principal functions: host or network interface identification and location addressing. Its role has been characterized as follows: "A name indicates what we seek. An address indicates where it is. A route indicates how to get there."</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/IP_address</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 28 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Domain name</word>
    <acronym>Domain</acronym>
    <description>A domain name is an identification string that defines a realm of administrative autonomy, authority, or control on the Internet. Domain names are formed by the rules and procedures of the Domain Name System (DNS).</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_name</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cb/DNS-names-ru.svg/220px-DNS-names-ru.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 29 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Uniform resource locator</word>
    <acronym>URL</acronym>
    <description>A URL is technically a type of uniform resource identifier (URI) but in many technical documents and verbal discussions URL is often used as a synonym for URI.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Uniform_resource_locator</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/c3/URI_Euler_Diagram_no_lone_URIs.svg/220px-URI_Euler_Diagram_no_lone_URIs.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>
</contents>
