<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<contents number="6" title="Software">
<!-- word 1 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Natural language</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Computational linguistics is an interdisciplinary field dealing with the statistical or rule-based modeling of natural language from a computational perspective. Traditionally, computational linguistics was usually performed by computer scientists who had specialized in the application of computers to the processing of a natural language. Computational linguists often work as members of interdisciplinary teams, including linguists (specifically trained in linguistics), language experts (persons with some level of ability in the languages relevant to a given project), and computer scientists.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computational_linguistics</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 2 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Programming language</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A programming language is an artificial language designed to communicate instructions to a machine, particularly a computer. Programming languages can be used to create programs that control the behavior of a machine and/or to express algorithms precisely.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Programming_language</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e1/Python_add5_syntax.svg/602px-Python_add5_syntax.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 3 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Computer program</word>
    <acronym>Program</acronym>
    <description>A computer program is a sequence of instructions written to perform a specified task with a computer. A computer requires programs to function, typically executing the program's instructions in a central processor. The program has an executable form that the computer can use directly to execute the instructions. The same program in its human-readable source code form, from which executable programs are derived (e.g., compiled), enables a programmer to study and develop its algorithms.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_program</link>
    <image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/-JNvG71GfXQI/Trf1SbiUNxI/AAAAAAAAASY/CbWSMf_X1pc/s400/lenguaje+de+programaci%25C3%25B3.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 4 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Source code</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computer science, source code is any collection of computer instructions (possibly with comments) written using some human-readable computer language, usually as text. The source code of a program is specially designed to facilitate the work of computer programmers, who specify the actions to be performed by a computer mostly by writing source code. The source code is automatically[clarification needed] translated at some point to machine code that the computer can directly read and execute. An interpreter translates to machine code[citation needed] and executes it on the fly when the program is run, while a compiler translates the program in advance to machine code that it stores as executable files; these can then be executed as a separate step.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Source_code</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/75/CodeCmmt002.svg/300px-CodeCmmt002.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 5 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Update</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In software, change or alter an application for a newer version of the same. This update can be for a patch, service pack or a full update of the program.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patch_(computing)</link>
    <image>http://recestudios.com/media/catalog/category/softwareUpdate-256.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 6 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>License</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The verb licence or grant licence means to give permission. The noun license or licence refers to that permission as well as to the document recording that permission. A licence may be granted by a party ("licensor") to another party as an element of an agreement between those parties. </description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/License</link>
    <image>http://www.itexecutive.com.kh/wp-content/uploads/Open-Source-Software-Licenses.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 7 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Algorithm</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In mathematics and computer science, an algorithm is a step by step procedure for calculations. Algorithms are used for calculation, data processing, and automated reasoning.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Algorithm</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/d3/Euclid_flowchart_1.png/220px-Euclid_flowchart_1.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 8 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Linux kernel</word>
    <acronym>Linux</acronym>
    <description>The Linux kernel is the operating system kernel used by the Linux family of Unix like operating systems. It is one of the most prominent examples of free and open source software.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Linux_kernel</link>
    <image>http://3.bp.blogspot.com/-RQWAgxFjnBw/Tny4BfOjyOI/AAAAAAAAAIw/xxaS4r3vqZE/s1600/Linux.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 9 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Virtual memory</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computing, virtual memory is a memory management technique developed for multitasking kernels. This technique virtualizes a computer architecture's various forms of computer data storage (such as random-access memory and disk storage), allowing a program to be designed as though there is only one kind of memory, "virtual" memory, which behaves like directly addressable read/write memory (RAM).</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_memory</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6e/Virtual_memory.svg/250px-Virtual_memory.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 10 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Software bug</word>
    <acronym>Bug</acronym>
    <description>A software bug is an error, flaw, mistake, failure, or fault in a computer program or system that produces an incorrect or unexpected result, or causes it to behave in unintended ways. Most bugs arise from mistakes and errors made by people in either a program's source code or its design, and a few are caused by compilers producing incorrect code.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Software_bug</link>
    <image>http://2.bp.blogspot.com/_iL7RGeRZj5w/TBWFvFpav2I/AAAAAAAAAjs/p6WvtfbZFlk/s1600/bug.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 11 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Microsoft Windows</word>
    <acronym>MS-Windows</acronym>
    <description>Microsoft Windows is a series of graphical interface operating systems developed, marketed, and sold by Microsoft. Microsoft introduced an operating environment named Windows on November 20, 1985 as an add-on to MS-DOS in response to the growing interest in graphical user interfaces (GUIs). Microsoft Windows came to dominate the world's personal computer market with over 90% market share, overtaking Mac OS, which had been introduced in 1984. The most recent client version of Windows is Windows 7; the most recent server version is Windows Server 2008 R2; the most recent mobile version is Windows Phone 7.5.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Microsoft_Windows</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/en/b/bd/Windows_7.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 12 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Compiler</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A compiler is a computer program (or set of programs) that transforms source code written in a programming language into another computer language. The most common reason for wanting to transform source code is to create an executable program.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Compiler</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6b/Compiler.svg/400px-Compiler.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 13 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Open source software</word>
    <acronym>OSS</acronym>
    <description>Open source software (OSS) is computer software that is available in source code form: the source code and certain other rights normally reserved for copyright holders are provided under an open source license that permits users to study, change, improve and at times also to distribute the software.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Open-source_software</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/42/Opensource.svg/220px-Opensource.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 14 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Copyright</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Copyright is a legal concept, enacted by most governments, giving the creator of an original work exclusive rights to it, usually for a limited time. Generally, it is "the right to copy", but also gives the copyright holder the right to be credited for the work, to determine who may adapt the work to other forms, who may perform the work, who may financially benefit from it, and other related rights. It is an intellectual property form applicable to any expressible form of an idea or information that is substantive and discrete.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Copyright</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/b0/Copyright.svg/200px-Copyright.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 15 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Integrated package</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>An integrated package is a group of applications ie one that consists of a number of distinct applications. E.g. a package that includes a word processor and spreadsheet and database</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Integrated_software</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 16 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Mozilla Application Suite</word>
    <acronym>Suite</acronym>
    <description>The Mozilla Application Suite was a cross platform integrated Internet suite. Its development was initiated by Netscape Communications Corporation, before their acquisition by AOL. It was based on the source code of Netscape Communicator. The Mozilla Suite was composed of several main programs: Navigator (a Web browser), Communicator (Mozilla Mail and Newsgroups), a Web page developer (Mozilla Composer), an IRC client (ChatZilla) and an electronic address book.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Mozilla_Application_Suite</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/35/Mozilla_1.7.png/250px-Mozilla_1.7.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 17 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Directory or folder</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computing, a directory, also referred to as a folder , catalog, or drawer, is a virtual container within a digital file system, in which groups of computer files and possibly other directories can be kept and organized. The technically correct name for such a file cataloging structure is directory, although names such as folder and drawer were adopted to provide some relevancy to the traditional office file cabinet.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Folder_%28computing%29</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9b/DirectoryListing1.png/300px-DirectoryListing1.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 18 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Patch</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A patch is a piece of software designed to fix problems with, or update a computer program or its supporting data. This includes fixing security vulnerabilities and other bugs, and improving the usability or performance. Though meant to fix problems, poorly designed patches can sometimes introduce new problems. In some special cases updates may knowingly break the functionality, for instance, by removing components for that the update provider is no longer licensed or disabling the jailbreaked device.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Patch_%28computing%29</link>
    <image>http://t2.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcSjVdy_MmVSZYS2BoFBVZX_P1oaGfWSNuAQnlmX_fNJTsIhJ-taXvdaRUFK</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 19 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Document</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Text file, document (a computer file that contains text (and possibly formatting instructions) using seven-bit ASCII characters).</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Document</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 20 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Shareware</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Shareware (also termed trialware or demoware) is proprietary software that is provided to users without payment on a trial basis and is often limited by any combination of functionality, availability (it may be functional for a limited time period only), or convenience (the software may present a dialog at startup or during usage, reminding the user to purchase it; "nagging dialogs").</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shareware</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 21 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Emulation</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The low-level simulation of equipment or phenomena by artificial means, such as by software modeling. Note that simulation may also allow an abstract high-level model.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Emulation</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 22 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Shell</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A shell is software that provides an interface for users of an operating system which provides access to the services of a kernel. However, the term is also applied very loosely to applications and may include any software that is "built around" a particular component, such as web browsers and email clients that are "shells" for HTML rendering engines. The name shell originates from shells being an outer layer of interface between the user and the internals of the operating system (the kernel).</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Shell_%28computing%29</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 23 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Operating system</word>
    <acronym>OS</acronym>
    <description>An operating system (OS) is a collection of software that manages computer hardware resources and provides common services for computer programs. The operating system is a vital component of the system software in a computer system. Application programs require an operating system to function.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Operating_system</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e1/Operating_system_placement.svg/165px-Operating_system_placement.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 24 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Desktop environment</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In graphical computing, a desktop environment (DE) commonly refers to a particular implementation of graphical user interface (GUI) derived from the desktop metaphor that is seen on most modern personal computers. These GUIs help the user in easily accessing, configuring, and modifying many important and frequently accessed specific operating system (OS) features. The GUI usually does not afford access to all the many features found in an OS.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Desktop_environment</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f7/Gnome_3.2_shell.png/800px-Gnome_3.2_shell.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 25 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>UNIX</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Unix is a multitasking, multi user computer operating system originally developed in 1969 by a group of AT and T employees at Bell Labs. The Unix operating system was first developed in assembly language, but by 1973 had been almost entirely recoded in C, greatly facilitating its further development and porting to other hardware.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/UNIX</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/77/Unix_history-simple.svg/800px-Unix_history-simple.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 26 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Computer file</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A computer file is a block of arbitrary information, or resource for storing information, which is available to a computer program and is usually based on some kind of durable storage. A file is durable in the sense that it remains available for programs to use after the current program has finished. Computer files can be considered as the modern counterpart of paper documents which traditionally are kept in offices' and libraries' files, and this is the source of the term.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_file</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 27 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Defragmentation</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In the maintenance of file systems, defragmentation is a process that reduces the amount of fragmentation. It does this by physically organizing the contents of the mass storage device used to store files into the smallest number of contiguous regions (fragments). It also attempts to create larger regions of free space using compaction to impede the return of fragmentation. Some defragmentation utilities try to keep smaller files within a single directory together, as they are often accessed in sequence.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Defragmentation</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/d/d0/FragmentationDefragmentation.gif</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 28 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Disk formatting</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Disk formatting is the process of preparing a hard disk drive or flexible disk medium for data storage. In some cases, the formatting operation may also create one or more new file systems. The formatting process that performs basic medium preparation is often referred to as "low-level formatting." The term "high-level formatting" most often refers to the process of generating a new file system. In certain operation systems, the two processes[clarification needed] are combined and the term "format" is understood to mean an operation in which a new disk medium is fully prepared to store files.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_formatting</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/95/Formatting-c-drive.JPG/220px-Formatting-c-drive.JPG</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 29 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Computer icon</word>
    <acronym>Icon</acronym>
    <description>A computer icon is a pictogram displayed on a computer screen and used to navigate a computer system or mobile device. The icon itself is a small picture or symbol serving as a quick, intuitive representation of a software tool, function or a data file accessible on the system. It functions as an electronic hyperlink or file shortcut to access the program or data.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_icon</link>
    <image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/3/36/Editor.pov_64x64.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 30 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>User interface</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The user interface, in the industrial design field of human machine interaction, is the space where interaction between humans and machines occurs. The goal of interaction between a human and a machine at the user interface is effective operation and control of the machine, and feedback from the machine which aids the operator in making operational decisions.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/User_interface</link>
    <image>http://t0.gstatic.com/images?q=tbn:ANd9GcTXPQovDJyZZ17PNxrDxpL-5Def9wV2fLYipDSicepv2Bh1yMTmrvR9N6P5rQ</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 31 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Natural language processing</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Natural language processing (NLP) is a field of computer science, artificial intelligence, and linguistics concerned with the interactions between computers and human (natural) languages. As such, NLP is related to the more general area of human computer interaction. Many challenges in NLP involve natural language understanding that is, enabling computers to derive meaning from human or natural language input.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Natural_language_processing</link>
    <image>http://speechdudes.files.wordpress.com/2012/08/nlp-graphic.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 32 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Upgrade</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The term upgrade refers to the replacement of a product with a newer version of the same product. It is most often used in computing and consumer electronics, generally meaning a replacement of hardware, software or firmware with a newer or better version, in order to bring the system up to date or to improve its characteristics. Contrast update and replace. See also laptop upgrade.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Upgrade</link>
    <image>None</image>
</vocabulary>
</contents>
