<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<contents number="4" title="Multimedia Advices (In/Out)">
<!-- word 1 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Red Green Blue</word>
    <acronym>RGB</acronym>
    <description>The RGB color model is an additive color model in which red, green, and blue light are added together in various ways to reproduce a broad array of colors. The name of the model comes from the initials of the three additive primary colors, red, green, and blue.
The main purpose of the RGB color model is for the sensing, representation, and display of images in electronic systems, such as televisions and computers, though it has also been used in conventional photography. Before the electronic age, the RGB color model already had a solid theory behind it, based in human perception of colors.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/RGB</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/28/RGB_illumination.jpg/200px-RGB_illumination.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 2 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Graphics processing unit</word>
    <acronym>GPU</acronym>
    <description>A graphics processing unit (GPU), also occasionally called visual processing unit (VPU), is a specialized electronic circuit designed to rapidly manipulate and alter memory to accelerate the building of images in a frame buffer intended for output to a display. GPUs are used in embedded systems, mobile phones, personal computers, workstations, and game consoles. Modern GPUs are very efficient at manipulating computer graphics, and their highly parallel structure makes them more effective than general-purpose CPUs for algorithms where processing of large blocks of data is done in parallel. In a personal computer, a GPU can be present on a video card, or it can be on the motherboard or on the CPU die. More than 90% of new desktop and notebook computers have integrated GPUs, which are usually far less powerful than those on a dedicated video card.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/GPU</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/44/6600GT_GPU.jpg/220px-6600GT_GPU.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 3 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Video RAM</word>
    <acronym>VRAM</acronym>
    <description>Video RAM, or VRAM, is a dual-ported variant of dynamic RAM (DRAM), which was once commonly used to store the framebuffer in some graphics adapters.
VRAM has two sets of data output pins, and thus two ports that can be used simultaneously. The first port, the DRAM port, is accessed by the host computer in a manner very similar to traditional DRAM. The second port, the video port, is typically read-only and is dedicated to providing a high throughput, serialized data channel for the graphics chipset.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VRAM</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9a/SEC_VRAM.jpg/220px-SEC_VRAM.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 4 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Computer monitor</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A monitor or display (also called screen or visual display unit) is an electronic visual display for computers. The monitor comprises the display device, circuitry, and an enclosure. The display device in modern monitors is typically a thin film transistor liquid crystal display (TFT-LCD) thin panel, while older monitors use a cathode ray tube (CRT) about as deep as the screen size.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_monitor</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/7e/LG_L194WT-SF_LCD_monitor.jpg/290px-LG_L194WT-SF_LCD_monitor.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 5 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Thin-film transistor monitor</word>
    <acronym>TFT monitor</acronym>
    <description>Thin film transistor liquid crystal display (TFT-LCD) is a variant of liquid crystal display (LCD) which uses thin-film transistor (TFT) technology to improve image quality (e.g., addressability, contrast). TFT LCD is an Active matrix LCD in contrast to Passive matrix LCDs or simple, direct-driven LCDs with a few segments. TFT LCDs are used in television sets, computer monitors, mobile phones, handheld video game systems, personal digital assistants, navigation systems, projectors, etc.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TFT_LCD</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 6 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Liquid crystal display</word>
    <acronym>LCD</acronym>
    <description>A liquid crystal display (LCD) is a flat panel display, electronic visual display, or video display that uses the light modulating properties of liquid crystals. Liquid crystals do not emit light directly.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Liquid_crystal_display</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dc/LCD_layers.svg/250px-LCD_layers.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 7 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Truecolor</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Truecolor graphics, or true color million colors used a method of storing image information in the computer memory where each pixel is represented by three or more bytes. The bits are divided into the component values ??for red, green and blue of the final color.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Color_depth#True_color_.2824-bit.29</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/6/69/Truecolor.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 8 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Musical Instrument Digital Interfac</word>
    <acronym>MIDI</acronym>
    <description>MIDI is an electronic musical instrument industry specification that enables a wide variety of digital musical instruments, computers and other related devices to connect and communicate with one another. It is a set of standard commands that allows electronic musical instruments, performance controllers, computers and related devices to communicate, as well as a hardware standard that guarantees compatibility between them.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MIDI</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/0a/Synth_rack_%40_Choking_Sun_Studio.jpg/220px-Synth_rack_%40_Choking_Sun_Studio.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 9 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Waveform Audio File Format</word>
    <acronym>WAV</acronym>
    <description>Waveform Audio File Format (WAVE, or more commonly known as WAV due to its filename extension), is a Microsoft and IBM audio file format standard for storing an audio bitstream on PCs.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/WAV</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 10 -->
<vocabulary>
	<word>Moving Picture Experts Group (MP3)</word>
	<acronym>MPEG</acronym>
	<description>MPEG-1 or MPEG-2 Audio Layer III, more commonly referred to as MP3, is a patented encoding format for digital audio which uses a form of lossy data compression. It is a common audio format for consumer audio storage, as well as a de facto standard of digital audio compression for the transfer and playback of music on digital audio players.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/MP3</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 11 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Digital audio</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Digital audio is sound reproduction using pulse-code modulation and digital signals. Digital audio systems include analog-to-digital conversion (ADC), digital-to-analog conversion (DAC), digital storage, processing and transmission components. A primary benefit of digital audio is in its convenience of storage, transmission and retrieval.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_audio</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/9a/Digital.signal.svg/220px-Digital.signal.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 12 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Synthesizer</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A sound synthesizer (often abbreviated as "synthesizer" or "synth") is an electronic instrument capable of producing a wide range of sounds. Synthesizers may either imitate other instruments ("imitative synthesis") or generate new timbres. They can be played (controlled) via a variety of different input devices (including keyboards, music sequencers and instrument controllers). Synthesizers generate electric signals (waveforms), and can finally be converted to sound through the loudspeakers or headphones.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Synthesizer</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 13 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Grayscale</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In photography and computing, a grayscale or greyscale digital image is an image in which the value of each pixel is a single sample, that is, it carries only intensity information. Images of this sort, also known as black-and-white, are composed exclusively of shades of gray, varying from black at the weakest intensity to white at the strongest.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grayscale</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 14 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Pixel</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In digital imaging, a pixel, or pel,(picture element) is a physical point in a raster image, or the smallest, addressable element in a display device; so it is the smallest, controllable element of a picture represented on the screen. The address of a pixel corresponds to its physical coordinates. LCD pixels are manufactured in a two-dimensional grid, and are often represented using dots or squares, but CRT pixels correspond to their timing mechanisms and sweep rates.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pixel</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/2/2b/Pixel-example.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 15 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Sub-pixel</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Many display and image-acquisition systems are, for various reasons, not capable of displaying or sensing the different color channels at the same site. Therefore, the pixel grid is divided into single-color regions that contribute to the displayed or sensed color when viewed at a distance. In some displays, such as LCD, LED, and plasma displays, these single-color regions are separately addressable elements, which have come to be known as subpixels. </description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sub-pixel#Subpixels</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4d/Pixel_geometry_01_Pengo.jpg/200px-Pixel_geometry_01_Pengo.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 16 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>BMP file format</word>
    <acronym>BMP</acronym>
    <description>The BMP file format, also known as bitmap image file or Device Independent Bitmap (DIB) file format or simply a bitmap, is a raster graphics image file format used to store bitmap digital images, independently of the display device (such as a graphics adapter), especially on Microsoft Windows and OS/2 operating systems.
The BMP file format is capable of storing 2D digital images of arbitrary width, height, and resolution, both monochrome and color, in various color depths, and optionally with data compression, alpha channels, and color profiles.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BMP_file_format</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 17 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Tagged Image File Format</word>
    <acronym>TIFF</acronym>
    <description>TIFF is a file format for storing images, popular among graphic artists, the publishing industry, and both amateur and professional photographers in general.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/TIFF</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 18 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Raw image format</word>
    <acronym>RAW</acronym>
    <description>A camera raw image file contains minimally processed data from the image sensor of either a digital camera, image scanner, or motion picture film scanner. Raw files are so named because they are not yet processed and therefore are not ready to be printed or edited with a bitmap graphics editor.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Raw_image_format</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 19 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Sampling rate</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The sampling rate, sample rate, or sampling frequency (f_s) defines the number of samples per unit of time (usually seconds) taken from a continuous signal to make a discrete signal.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sampling_rate</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a5/Analog_digital_series.svg/220px-Analog_digital_series.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 20 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Video Graphics Array</word>
    <acronym>VGA</acronym>
    <description>Video Graphics Array (VGA) refers specifically to the display hardware first introduced with the IBM PS/2 line of computers in 1987, but through its widespread adoption has also come to mean either an analog computer display standard, the 15-pin D-subminiature VGA connector or the 640x480 resolution itself. While this resolution was superseded in the personal computer market in the 1990s, it is becoming a popular resolution on mobile devices.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/VGA</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>
</contents>
