<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<contents number="5" title="Peripherals">
<!-- word 1 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Pointing device</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A pointing device is an input interface (specifically a human interface device) that allows a user to input spatial (i.e., continuous and multi-dimensional) data to a computer. CAD systems and graphical user interfaces (GUI) allow the user to control and provide data to the computer using physical gestures for example, by moving a hand-held mouse across the surface of the physical desktop and activating switches on the mouse. Movements of the pointing device are echoed on the screen by movements of the pointer (or cursor) and other visual changes.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pointing_device</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/79/Logitech_Mouse.JPG/220px-Logitech_Mouse.JPG</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 2 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Mini-DV</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Small cassettes, also known as S-size or MiniDV cassettes, had been intended for amateur use, but have become accepted in professional productions as well. MiniDV cassettes are used for recording baseline DV, DVCAM as well as HDV.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DV#Magnetic_tape</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/27/DV_tape_sizes_2.jpg/250px-DV_tape_sizes_2.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 3 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Plotter</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>The plotter is a computer printer for printing vector graphics. In the past, plotters were used in applications such as computer-aided design, though they have generally been replaced with wide-format conventional printers. It is now commonplace to refer to such wide-format printers as "plotters," even though they technically are not.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Plotter</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/89/ColorPlotter.jpg/300px-ColorPlotter.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 4 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Display device</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A display device is an output device for presentation of information in visual[1] or tactile form (the latter used for example in tactile electronic displays for blind people). When the input information is supplied as an electrical signal, the display is called an electronic display.
Common applications for electronic visual displays are televisions or computer monitors.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Display_device</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/1e/Anzeigen%28Displays%29.jpg/240px-Anzeigen%28Displays%29.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 5 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Optical character recognition</word>
    <acronym>OCR</acronym>
    <description>Optical character recognition, usually abbreviated to OCR, is the mechanical or electronic conversion of scanned images of handwritten, typewritten or printed text into machine-encoded text. It is widely used as a form of data entry from some sort of original paper data source, whether documents, sales receipts, mail, or any number of printed records. It is a common method of digitizing printed texts so that they can be electronically searched, stored more compactly, displayed on-line, and used in machine processes such as machine translation, text-to-speech and text mining. OCR is a field of research in pattern recognition, artificial intelligence and computer vision.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Optical_character_recognition</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 6 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Inkjet printing</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Inkjet printing is a type of computer printing that creates a digital image by propelling droplets of ink onto paper. Inkjet printers are the most commonly used type of printer, and range from small inexpensive consumer models to very large professional machines that can cost tens of thousands of dollars.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Inkjet_printing</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/eb/Epson-inkjet-printer.jpg/220px-Epson-inkjet-printer.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 7 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Laser printing</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Laser printing is a digital printing process that rapidly produces high quality text and graphics on plain paper. As with digital photocopiers and multifunction printers (MFPs), laser printers employ a xerographic printing process, but differ from analog photocopiers in that the image is produced by the direct scanning of a laser beam across the printer's photoreceptor.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Laser_printing</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/b/b8/Hp_laserjet_4200dtns.jpg/220px-Hp_laserjet_4200dtns.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 8 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Dot matrix printer</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A dot matrix printer or impact matrix printer is a type of computer printer with a print head that runs back and forth, or in an up and down motion, on the page and prints by impact, striking an ink-soaked cloth ribbon against the paper, much like the print mechanism on a typewriter. However, unlike a typewriter or daisy wheel printer, letters are drawn out of a dot matrix, and thus, varied fonts and arbitrary graphics can be produced. Because the printing involves mechanical pressure, these printers can create carbon copies and carbonless copies. Its speed of printing varies from 50 to 500 cps.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dot_matrix_printer</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/24/Printer_dot_matrix_EPSON_VP-500.jpg/180px-Printer_dot_matrix_EPSON_VP-500.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 9 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Digital camera</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A digital camera (or digicam) is a camera that takes video or still photographs by recording images on an electronic image sensor. Most cameras sold today are digital[1], and digital cameras are incorporated into many devices ranging from PDAs and mobile phones (called camera phones) to vehicles.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_camera</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/9/99/Canon_PowerShot_A95_-_front_and_back.jpg/220px-Canon_PowerShot_A95_-_front_and_back.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 10 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Joystick</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A joystick is an input device consisting of a stick that pivots on a base and reports its angle or direction to the device it is controlling. A joystick, also known as the control column, is the principal control device in the cockpit of many civilian and military aircraft, either as a center stick or side-stick. It often has supplementary switches to control various aspects of the aircraft's flight.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Joystick</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/d/dd/Joyopis.svg/200px-Joyopis.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 11 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Computer keyboard</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computing, a keyboard is a typewriter-style keyboard, which uses an arrangement of buttons or keys, to act as mechanical levers or electronic switches. Following the decline of punch cards and paper tape, interaction via teleprinter-style keyboards became the main input device for computers.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_keyboard</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/fa/Alphanumeric_keyboard.jpg/220px-Alphanumeric_keyboard.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 12 -->
<vocabulary>
	<word>Digitizing</word>
	<acronym>None</acronym>
	<description>Digitizing or digitization is the representation of an object, image, sound, document or a signal (usually an analog signal) by a discrete set of its points or samples. The result is called digital representation or, more specifically, a digital image, for the object, and digital form, for the signal. Strictly speaking, digitizing means simply capturing an analog signal in digital form.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digitalizing</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 13 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Image scanner</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computing, an image scanner is a device that optically scans images, printed text, handwriting, or an object, and converts it to a digital image.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Image_scanner</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/e/e3/Scanner.view.750pix.jpg/220px-Scanner.view.750pix.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 14 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Cyan, magenta, yellow, and key color model</word>
    <acronym>CMYK</acronym>
    <description>The CMYK color model (process color, four color) is a subtractive color model, used in color printing, and is also used to describe the printing process itself. CMYK refers to the four inks used in some color printing: cyan, magenta, yellow, and key (black). Though it varies by print house, press operator, press manufacturer, and press run, ink is typically applied in the order of the abbreviation.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CMYK</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/4/4c/CMYK_color_swatches.svg/150px-CMYK_color_swatches.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 15 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Actuator</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>An actuator is a type of motor for moving or controlling a mechanism or system. It is operated by a source of energy, usually in the form of an electric current, hydraulic fluid pressure or pneumatic pressure, and converts that energy into some kind of motion. An actuator is the mechanism by which an agent acts upon an environment. The agent can be either an artificial intelligence agent or any other autonomous being (human, other animal, etc.).</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Actuator</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 16 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Sensor</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A sensor (also called detector) is a converter that measures a physical quantity and converts it into a signal which can be read by an observer or by an (today mostly electronic) instrument.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sensor</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/88/Type_K_and_type_S.jpg/220px-Type_K_and_type_S.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 17 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Light pen</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A light pen, also called a selector pen, is a computer input device in the form of a light-sensitive wand used in conjunction with a computer's CRT display. It allows the user to point to displayed objects or draw on the screen in a similar way to a touchscreen but with greater positional accuracy. It was long thought[according to whom? that a light pen can work with any CRT-based display, but not with LCDs and other display technologies.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Light_pen</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cd/HypertextEditingSystemConsoleBrownUniv1969.jpg/220px-HypertextEditingSystemConsoleBrownUniv1969.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 18 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>QWERTY</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>QWERTY is the most common modern-day keyboard layout. The name comes from the first six letters (keys) appearing in the top left letter row of the keyboard, read left to right: Q-W-E-R-T-Y. The QWERTY design is based on a layout created for the Sholes and Glidden typewriter and sold to Remington in the same year, when it first appeared in typewriters.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/QWERTY</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/0a/QWERTY_keyboard.jpg/250px-QWERTY_keyboard.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 19 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Dvorak Simplified Keyboard</word>
    <acronym>DVORAK</acronym>
    <description>The Dvorak Simplified Keyboard is a keyboard layout patented in 1936 by Dr. August Dvorak and his brother-in-law, Dr. William Dealey. Over the years several slight variations were designed by the team led by Dvorak or by ANSI. These variations have been collectively or individually also called the Simplified Keyboard or American Simplified Keyboard but they all have come to be commonly known as the Dvorak keyboard or Dvorak layout.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dvorak_Simplified_Keyboard</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/25/KB_United_States_Dvorak.svg/400px-KB_United_States_Dvorak.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!-- word 20 -->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Keycode</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A key code is a series of alphanumeric characters used by locksmiths to create a key. There are two kinds of key codes: blind codes and bitting codes.</description>
    <link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Key_code</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>
</contents>
