<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<contents number="2" title="Storing">
<!--First word-->
<vocabulary>
	<word>Primary Storage</word>
	<acronym>None</acronym>
	<description>Primary storage (or main memory or internal memory), often referred to simply as memory, is the only one directly accessible to the CPU. The CPU continuously reads instructions stored there and executes them as required. Any data actively operated on is also stored there in uniform manner.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_data_storage#Primary_storage</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/3/3e/Computer_storage_types.svg/350px-Computer_storage_types.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Second word-->
<vocabulary>
	<word>Secundary Storage</word>
	<acronym>None</acronym>
	<description>Secondary storage (also known as external memory or auxiliary storage), differs from primary storage in that it is not directly accessible by the CPU. The computer usually uses its input/output channels to access secondary storage and transfers the desired data using intermediate area in primary storage. Secondary storage does not lose the data when the device is powered down—it is non-volatile. Per unit, it is typically also two orders of magnitude less expensive than primary storage. Consequently, modern computer systems typically have two orders of magnitude more secondary storage than primary storage and data are kept for a longer time there. In modern computers, hard disk drives are usually used as secondary storage. The time taken to access a given byte of information stored on a hard disk is typically a few thousandths of a second, or milliseconds. By contrast, the time taken to access a given byte of information stored in random access memory is measured in billionths of a second, or nanoseconds. This illustrates the significant access-time difference which distinguishes solid-state memory from rotating magnetic storage devices: hard disks are typically about a million times slower than memory. Rotating optical storage devices, such as CD and DVD drives, have even longer access times. With disk drives, once the disk read/write head reaches the proper placement and the data of interest rotates under it, subsequent data on the track are very fast to access. As a result, in order to hide the initial seek time and rotational latency, data are transferred to and from disks in large contiguous blocks.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Computer_data_storage#Secondary_storage</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/1/1d/Hard_disk_platter_reflection.jpg/220px-Hard_disk_platter_reflection.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Third word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Hard Disk Drive</word>
    <acronym>HDD</acronym>
    <description>A hard disk drive (HDD, also hard drive, hard disk, or disk drive)is a device for storing and retrieving digital information, primarily computer data. It consists of one or more rigid (hence "hard") rapidly rotating discs (platters) coated with magnetic material, and with magnetic heads arranged to write data to the surfaces and read it from them.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Hard_disk_drive</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/cf/HardDisk1.ogg/mid-HardDisk1.ogg.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Fourth word-->
<vocabulary>
	<word>Random-Access Memory</word>
	<acronym>RAM</acronym>
	<description>Random-access memory (RAM) is a form of computer data storage. A random access device allows stored data to be accessed in any order in very nearly the same amount of time for any storage location or size of memory device. A device such as a magnetic tape requires increasing time to access data stored on parts of the tape that are far from the ends. Memory devices (such as floppy discs, CDs and DVDs) can access the storage data only in a predetermined order, because of mechanical design limitations; the time to access a given part of the device varies significantly due to its physical location.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random-access_memory</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/c/ca/Memory_module_DDRAM_20-03-2006.jpg/220px-Memory_module_DDRAM_20-03-2006.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Fifth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Read-Only memory</word>
    <acronym>ROM</acronym>
    <description>Read-only memory (ROM) is a class of storage medium used in computers and other electronic devices. Data stored in ROM cannot be modified, or can be modified only slowly or with difficulty, so it is mainly used to distribute firmware (software that is very closely tied to specific hardware, and unlikely to need frequent updates).</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Read-only_memory</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/f/f8/ROM_.jpg/220px-ROM_.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Sixth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Cache memory</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>A CPU cache is a cache used by the central processing unit of a computer to reduce the average time to access memory. The cache is a smaller, faster memory which stores copies of the data from the most frequently used main memory locations. As long as most memory accesses are cached memory locations, the average latency of memory accesses will be closer to the cache latency than to the latency of main memory.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CPU_cache</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Seventh word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Basic Input Output System</word>
    <acronym>BIOS</acronym>
    <description>The BIOS software is built into the PC  and is the first code run by a PC when powered on ('boot firmware'). When the PC starts up, the first job for the BIOS is the power-on self-test, which initializes and identifies system devices such as the CPU, RAM, video display card, keyboard and mouse, hard disk drive, optical disc drive and other hardware. The BIOS then locates boot loader software held on a peripheral device (designated as a 'boot device'), such as a hard disk or a CD/DVD, and loads and executes that software, giving it control of the PC. This process is known as booting, or booting up, which is short for bootstrapping.
BIOS software is stored on a non-volatile ROM chip on the motherboard. It is specifically designed to work with each particular model of computer, interfacing with various devices that make up the complementary chipset of the system. In modern computer systems the BIOS chip's contents can be rewritten without removing it from the motherboard, allowing BIOS software to be upgraded in place.
A BIOS has a user interface (UI), typically a menu system accessed by pressing a certain key on the keyboard when the PC starts.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/BIOS</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/0/05/Award_BIOS_setup_utility.png/220px-Award_BIOS_setup_utility.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Eighth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Firmware</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In electronic systems and computing, firmware is the combination of persistent memory and program code and data stored in it. Typical examples of devices containing firmware are embedded systems (such as traffic lights, consumer appliances, and digital watches), computers, computer peripherals, mobile phones, and digital cameras. The firmware contained in these devices provides the control program for the device. Firmware is held in non-volatile memory devices such as ROM, EPROM, or flash memory. </description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Firmware</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/7/7f/Television_remote_control.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Nineth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Flash memory</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Flash memory is a non-volatile/permanent storage memory' computer storage chip that can be electrically erased and reprogrammed. It was developed from EEPROM (electrically erasable programmable read-only memory) and must be erased in fairly large blocks before these can be rewritten with new data. The high density NAND type must also be programmed and read in (smaller) blocks, or pages, while the NOR type allows a single machine word (byte) to be written or read independently.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Flash_memory</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/2/2c/USB_flash_drive.JPG/220px-USB_flash_drive.JPG</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Tenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Bit rate</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In telecommunications and computing, bit rate (sometimes written bitrate, data rate or as a variable R) is the number of bits that are conveyed or processed per unit of time.
The bit rate is quantified using the bits per second (bit/s or bps) unit, often in conjunction with an SI prefix such as kilo- (kbit/s or kbps), mega- (Mbit/s or Mbps), giga- (Gbit/s or Gbps) or tera- (Tbit/s or Tbps). Note that, unlike many other computer-related units, 1 kbit/s is traditionally defined as 1,000-bit/s, not 1,024-bit/s, etc., also before 1999 when SI prefixes were introduced for units of information in the standard IEC 60027-2. Uppercase K as in Kbit/s or Kbps should never be used.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bit_rate</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Eleventh word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Virtual memory</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computing, virtual memory is a memory management technique developed for multitasking kernels. This technique virtualizes a computer architecture's various forms of computer data storage (such as random-access memory and disk storage), allowing a program to be designed as though there is only one kind of memory, "virtual" memory, which behaves like directly addressable read/write memory (RAM).</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Virtual_memory</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/6e/Virtual_memory.svg/250px-Virtual_memory.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Twelfth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Random access</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computer science, random access (sometimes called direct access) is the ability to access an element at an arbitrary position in a sequence in equal time, independent of sequence size. The position is arbitrary in the sense that it is unpredictable, thus the use of the term "random" in "random access". The opposite is sequential access, where a remote element takes longer time to access</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Random_access</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a7/Random_vs_sequential_access.svg/220px-Random_vs_sequential_access.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Thirteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Sequential access</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>In computer science, sequential access means that a group of elements (e.g. data in a memory array or a disk file or on magnetic tape data storage) is accessed in a predetermined, ordered sequence. Sequential access is sometimes the only way of accessing the data, for example if it is on a tape. It may also be the access method of choice, for example if we simply want to process a sequence of data elements in order.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sequential_access</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a7/Random_vs_sequential_access.svg/220px-Random_vs_sequential_access.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Fourteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Disk partitioning</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Disk partitioning is the act of dividing a hard disk drive into multiple logical storage units referred to as partitions, to treat one physical disk drive as if it were multiple disks. Partitions are also termed "slices" for operating systems based on BSD, Solaris or GNU Hurd. A partition editor software program can be used to create, resize, delete, and manipulate these partitions on the hard disk.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Disk_partitioning</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/6/64/GParted.png/300px-GParted.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Fifteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Rotational speed</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Rotational speed (sometimes called speed of revolution) is the number of complete rotations or revolutions per time unit. Rotational speed is a cyclic frequency measured in hertz ("rotations per minute or per second") in the SI System or revolutions per minute or per second (rpm or 1/min), the latter of which is more common in everyday life. Scientists, however, generally prefer to measure rotational speed in radians per second.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Rotational_speed</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Sixteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Access time</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>Access time is the time delay or latency between a request to an electronic system, and the access being completed or the requested data returned. In a computer, it is the time interval between the instant at which an instruction control unit initiates a call for data or a request to store data, and the instant at which delivery of the data is completed or the storage is started.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Access_time</link>
	<image>one</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Seventeenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Floppy disk</word>
    <acronym>FDD</acronym>
    <description>A floppy disk, or diskette, is a disk storage medium composed of a disk of thin and flexible magnetic storage medium, sealed in a rectangular plastic carrier lined with fabric that removes dust particles.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Floppy_disk</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/aa/Floppy_disk_2009_G1.jpg/220px-Floppy_disk_2009_G1.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Eighteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>1x or 52x (CD-RW drive)</word>
    <acronym>None</acronym>
    <description>CD-RW drives will typically have three speed ratings - one for reading discs, one for writing CD-R discs and another for writing CD-RW discs. Speed ratings vary from 1x to 52x, where 1x means that a CD is written/read in 'real time' - a 52 minute audio CD would take about 52 minutes to create at 1x speed, and about 1 minute at 52x speed.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/Computer_Hardware#CD-ROM_drive</link>
	<image>None</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Nineteenth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>USB flash drive</word>
    <acronym>USB</acronym>
    <description>A USB flash drive is a data storage device that includes flash memory with an integrated Universal Serial Bus (USB) interface. USB flash drives are typically removable and rewritable, and physically much smaller than a floppy disk. Most weigh less than 30 g.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/USB_flash_drive</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/86/SanDisk_Cruzer_Micro.png/220px-SanDisk_Cruzer_Micro.png</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Twentieth word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Digital Audio Tape</word>
    <acronym>DAT</acronym>
    <description>Digital Audio Tape (DAT or R-DAT) is a signal recording and playback medium developed by Sony and introduced in 1987. In appearance it is similar to a compact audio cassette, using 4 mm magnetic tape enclosed in a protective shell, but is roughly half the size at 73 mm × 54 mm × 10.5 mm. As the name suggests, the recording is digital rather than analog. DAT has the ability to record at higher, equal or lower sampling rates than a CD (48, 44.1 or 32 kHz sampling rate respectively) at 16 bits quantization. If a digital source is copied then the DAT will produce an exact clone, unlike other digital media such as Digital Compact Cassette or non-Hi-MD MiniDisc, both of which use a lossy data reduction system.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Digital_Audio_Tape</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/a/a9/Dat_cartridge.jpg/250px-Dat_cartridge.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Twenty-first word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Decision support system</word>
    <acronym>DSS</acronym>
    <description>A decision support system (DSS) is a computer-based information system that supports business or organizational decision-making activities. DSSs serve the management, operations, and planning levels of an organization and help to make decisions, which may be rapidly changing and not easily specified in advance.</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Decision_support_system</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/7/74/Decision_Support_System_for_John_Day_Reservoir.jpg/360px-Decision_Support_System_for_John_Day_Reservoir.jpg</image>
</vocabulary>

<!--Twenty-second word-->
<vocabulary>
    <word>Complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor</word>
    <acronym>CMOS</acronym>
    <description>Complementary metal-oxide-semiconductor (CMOS) is a technology for constructing integrated circuits. CMOS technology is used in microprocessors, microcontrollers, static RAM, and other digital logic circuits. CMOS technology is also used for several analog circuits such as image sensors (CMOS sensor), data converters, and highly integrated transceivers for many types of communication. Frank Wanlass patented CMOS in 1967</description>
	<link>http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/CMOS</link>
	<image>http://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/thumb/8/81/CMOS_Inverter.svg/220px-CMOS_Inverter.svg.png</image>
</vocabulary>
</contents>
